HAARIS MALIK

haaris.malik416@gmail.com +1-647-640-7860

haarismalik.ca | linkedin.com/in/haarismalik-/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY -

An experienced and highly motivated frontend developer with a strong passion for learning and building websites that provide a great user experience with great UI design's for better user navigation. I have adminstrative experience and have experience working with buisness's/company's, working towards solving buisness problems and fulfilling important tasks.

EDUCATION -

Interaction Design and Development | Advanced Diploma (AA)

George Brown College School of Design - Toronto, Ontario

Jan 2019 - Apr 2021

EXPERIENCE -

Freelance | Frontend Developer

Remote | Oct 2021 - Present

- Engineered scalable, responsive, multi-platform and SEO friendly websites for my projects using HTML5, CSS3 + BEM, JavaScript ES6+ and React best practises.
- Implemented design practises for UX/UI components to obtain better design/user flow within applications.
- Connected to backend API'S through CRUD HTTP requests.

Philthy Philly's | Key Holder/Supervisor

RichmondHill, Ontario | Sep 2017 - Feb 2022

- Supervised employees on the job and I was apart of the recruitment team for the buisness.
- Mentored co-workers and made sure to guide them and give clear intructions for tasks to be fulfilled.
- Open and closed buisness depending on shift (night/day) and also counted cash register, daily profit's and earnings at the end of the shift. Made sure to keep track of inventory and record the right quantity needed.
- Interacted with customers and took care of their orders and made sure of achieving customer satisfaction every time.

TECHNICAL SKILLS -

Proficient: HTML/HTML5 & CSS/CSS3 (BEM), JavaScript ES6+, React.JS, Git, GitHub, Bootstrap, Figma, Adobe Illustrator

Familiar: Redux, SASS, Excel, React Dev Tools

Design Practises: User Testing, User Research, Branding, Responsive Website Development, Prototyping & Wireframing, User Interface Design

PROJECTS EXPERIENCE

Online Book Store | https://haarismalik.github.io/E-CommerceWebsite/

- Designed and developing using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6+ and React.JS.
- The app is a prototype of a book store that I designed with multi-platform support, updated with the latest books out.
- full responsivness and functionality, with a clean simplistic design for users to easily navigate through.

Corpus | link available at haarismalik.ca

- Concept pharmaceutical app designed to keep track of medicine and being able to pull up intructions on how to take medicine with the ability to scan the medicine.
- Early prototyping required research and case studies. Optimized UX/UI to fit the personas in place for the application.
- Built the user interface and wireframes using Figma with multiple screen and functionality concepts. Worked In a team enviroment.

E-Portfolio | haarismalik.ca

- Designed, developed and hosted my e-portfolio using semantic HTML5, CSS3 (+BEM) and JavaScript ES6+ best practises.
- Included responsive and multi-platform support enabling the portfolio to be viewed on any platform and device. Showcases all my projects.